Guide to the Leonard Sirowitz papers, 1947-2008 and undated RL.11262
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Leonard Sirowitz papers
1947-2008 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sirowitz, Leonard
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11262
9.0 Linear Feet
Art Director and advertising executive at Doyle Dane Bernbach and partner in several independent agencies. Includes clippings, proofs of print advertisements, video cassettes of television commercials, photographs and slidIncludes clippings, proofs of print advertisements, video cassettes of television commercials, photographs and slides, writings, texts of speeches; award certificates, ces, writings, texts of speeches; award certificates, correspondence and other printed materials relating to Sirowitz's career at Doyle Dane Bernbach and independent agencies co-founded with Ron Rosenfeld and Marion Harper. Companies represented include Bain de Soleil, Better Vision Institute, Champion International, El Al Airlines, Mobil, Sony, Volkswagen and Yugo. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: Professional Files; Print Advertisements; Writings and Speeches; and Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Born 1932, Brooklyn, N.Y.; 1953 Pratt Institute (Advertising Design); 1953 L.W. Frohlich; 1953-1955 military service, U.S. Army; 1955 Grey Advertising; 1956 Columbia Broadcasting; 1957 Art Department, NTA Television Network; 1959 Art Director, Doyle Dane Bernbach; 1968, 1970 voted "Number One Art Director in America" in national Ad Daily polls; 1969 Senior Vice President, DDB; 1970 partner, Harper Rosenfeld Sirowitz (renamed Rosenfeld Sirowitz & Lawson the same year, became Rosenfeld Sirowitz Humphrey & Strauss in 1986); 1982-1983 President, One Club for Art and Copy; 1984 Honorary Doctorate of Fine Arts, Pratt Institute; 1985 Art Directors Hall of Fame.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed to researchers until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Leonard Sirowitz papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2016.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections: Arthur Einstein papers; Gotham, Inc. records; Jacqueline End papers; Lore Parker papers; Margaret Fishback papers; Simon Kornblit papers; Thomas F. Garbett papers.
Collection Overview
Includes clippings, proofs of print advertisements, video cassettes of television commercials, photographs and slides, writings, texts of speeches, award certificates, correspondence and other printed materials relating to Sirowitz's career at Doyle Dane Bernbach and independent agencies co-founded with Ron Rosenfeld and Marion Harper. Companies represented include Bain de Soleil, Better Vision Institute, Champion International, El Al Airlines, Mobil, Sony, Volkswagen and Yugo. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States -- Design; Advertising executives; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Professional Files, 1947-2008 and undated; 1
  - Awards, 1961-1984 and undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Awards, 1961-1982 (Box 10)
  - Awards--Ad Daily, 1967-1972 (Box 1)
  - Awards--Advertising Club of New York (Andy Award), 1964-1979; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Awards--Advertising Club of New York, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
  - Awards--Advertising Writers Association of New York, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Awards--AIGA (American Institute of Graphic Arts), 1960-1965 (Box 1)
  - Awards--AIGA (American Institute of Graphic Arts), 1959-1969 (Box 10)
  - Awards--Art Directors Club of New York, 1959-1967 (Box 1)
  - Awards--Art Directors Club of New York, 1959-1984 (Box 10)
  - Awards--Art Directors Hall of Fame, 1985-1991 (Box 1)
  - Awards--CA Magazine, 1961-1967 (Box 1)
  - Awards--CLIO, 1982-1987 (Box 10)
  - Awards--Newspaper Advertising Bureau, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Awards--Pratt Institute (honorary doctorate), 1983 (Box 1)
  - Awards--Type Directors Club of New York, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
  - Biographical sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Cards, stationery, etc., undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1964-2008; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1947-1995; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Clippings--Yedioth Ahronoth (article on making of a Hero detergent commercial in Israel, in Hebrew), 1968 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1990 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Doyle Dane Bernbach years, 1964-1969 (Box 1)
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach, 1965-1984 (Box 1)
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--Clippings, 1965-1969 (Box 1)
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--Clippings, 1964-1980; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--Memoranda, 1964-1969 (Box 2)
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--Newsletters, 1964-1979 (Box 2)
  - Harper Rosenfeld Sirowitz--Clippings, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Harper Rosenfeld Sirowitz (Marion Harper)--Clippings, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Photographs, undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 5)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 11)
  - Photographs--Negatives, undated (Box 3)
  - Photographs--With Oscar Robertson, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Photographs--With Jerry Lewis, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Photographs--Slides, undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Pratt Institute newsletters and clippings, 1979-1992 (Box 10)
  - Print advertisements--Crimestoppers, Royal Caribbean, Sharp, 1984-1991 (Box 3)
  - Print advertisements--Pratt Institute, undated (Box 3)
  - Print material--Chateau Vintage Vehicles, undated (Box 3)
  - Print material--Sara Lee Kitchen Talk, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Print material--Tribute to William Golden, circa 1964 (Box 3)
  - Ron Rosenfeld (includes memorials), 1969-1997 (Box 10)
  - Rosenfeld Sirowitz Lawson--Clippings, 1969-1986; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Rosenfeld Sirowitz Humphrey Strauss--Clippings, 1986-1994; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Sketch of automobile for Mobil advocacy campaign, undated (Box 3)
- Writings and Speeches, 1967-1996 and undated; 2
  - A Beautiful Picture of Something is Better Than a Beautiful Picture of Nothing, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Ad Age Workshop--Bill Bernbach Day, circa 1975 (Box 4)
  - ADC presentation (English and Japanese), 1987 (Box 4)
  - Advice to a Young Man or Woman Who Is Thinking of Becoming an Art Director, undated (Box 4)
  - Art Directors Hall of Fame (Herschel Levit), 1989 (Box 4)
  - Better Vision Institute Selling Propositions, undated (Box 4)
  - Collier Seminar, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Creativity in the 70s, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Don't Just Take Up Space (My Advertising Philosophy), undated (Box 4)
  - George Lois/Hershel Levit Award, undated (Box 4)
  - Hall of Fame talks, 1987-1990 (Box 4)
  - Herschel Levit tribute, undated (Box 4)
  - Japan Update, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Laundry for a Million Pounds, undated (Box 4)
  - Lever speech, undated (Box 4)
  - Mainichi Broadcasting System/Comparative Advertising, undated (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
  - Mogen David sales meeting, 1977 (Box 4)
  - One Club, undated (Box 4)
  - One Show speech, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Open Message to the Best Ex-Creative People in Our Business, undated (Box 4)
  - Pratt Institute exhibit, Let's Put Design in Its Place, undated (Box 4)
  - Pratt Institute speech, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Presentation for the Training Group, undated (Box 4)
  - RS (Box 4)
  - San Diego speech, undated (Box 4)
  - Talk on Creative Function, undated (Box 4)
  - Ten Tips on Improving Your Writing and Eight Ways to Give Better Presentations, undated (Box 4)
  - Zurich speech (in German), reprinted in Die Idee, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Zurich talk (English and German), 1967 (Box 4)
  - Zurich talk (Don Trevor), 1968 (Box 4)
- Print Advertisements, 1960-1994 and undated; 3
  - Bain de Soleil, 1988-1994; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Better Vision Institute, undated (Box 6)
  - Better Vision Institute, undated (Box 7)
  - Champion International, 1981-1984 (Box 9)
  - Coalition for a Democratic Alternative (Eugene McCarthy for President), circa 1968 (Box 12)
  - Coalition for National Priorities, undated (Box 12)
  - El Al Airlines, undated (Box 12)
  - El Al, NTA International, Ohrbach's, Rosenfeld Sirowitz, 1960-1968 and undated (Box 9)
  - MacNaughton Canadian Whiskey, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Mobil traffic safety, undated (Box 8)
  - Mobil traffic safety, undated (Box 12)
  - Mobil traffic safety (DDB; Len and Bob Levenson), 1966 (Box 14)
  - Rainier Beer, undated (Box 12)
  - Redbook Magazine, 1983-1991; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Rosenfeld Sirowitz Humphrey, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Rosenfeld Sirowitz Lawson (Box 8)
  - Rosenfeld Sirowitz Lawson, 1979-1985 (Box 13)
  - Rosenfeld Sirowitz Humphrey Strauss portfolio, 1982-1986 and undated (Box 14)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes Ad Council for Food Stamps, Smith Corona, Automobile Magazine, Delta Faucet, Yugo, Sea Ray Boats; some with Marty Wolf, Art Director
  - Royal Caribbean Cruise Lines, 1991-1992; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - SANE (National Committee for an Sane Nuclear Policy), undated (Box 13)
  - SANE, Rainier Beer newsprint, undated (Box 14)
  - Schenley SA Gin, undated (Box 13)
  - Sharp, 1977 and undated (Box 9)
  - Sony (Box 8)
  - Sony TV, undated (Box 13)
  - Vietnam Moratorium Committee, undated (Box 13)
  - Volkswagen (DDB), 1960s (Box 14)
  - Volkswagen, NTA (National Telefilm Associates), Rainier Beer, undated (Box 14)
  - WABC-TV, undated (Box 13)
  - Yugo, 1985 (Box 11)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1978-2003 and undated; 4
  - 4-A's historical reel, 1992 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-001, Digital-materials RL11262-SET-0001)
    Bowmar "Brain"; Geritol "My Wife"; John Hancock "Boats"; WABC-TV "X-Mas"; McDonald's "Big Mac Big"; Colibri "Butterfly"; Smith Corona "Dr. Ruth"; Delta "Water Ballet"; America West "Air Superiority"; Royal Caribbean "Image". TRT: 10:00.
  - Hall of Fame reel, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-002, Digital-materials RL11262-SET-0001)
    Mobil "Ten Story Building" "I'm Going Driving"; Laura Scudders "Pledge"; VW "Plow"; Champion "Broadway"; Yugo "Model T"; plus print ads. TRT: 10:00.
  - RS, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-003)
    Mobil, Laura Scudders, VW, Parker, Sara Lee. TRT: 15:10
  - Golden Oldies Pratt Presentation TV/Print. TRT: 10:00., 2003 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-004)
  - Champion International spots, 1984 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-005)
    ET#680. Champion "Playground" "Broadway" "Judo" work print/work track. TRT: 2:00.
  - RS, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-006)
    RS&L library copy: McDonald's "Big Mac Big"; Calibri "Butterfly"; Chase "I'm Sorry"; Smith Corona "Dr. Ruth"; Forever Krystle "The Perfume"; Delta "Water Ballet"; Jhirmack "Forget Everything"; Champion "Broadway"; Yugo "Model T".
  - Golden Oldies demo reel, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-007)
    Mobil "Bridge"; Laura Scudder "Playground"; VW "Paint". TRT: 3:00.
  - Volkswagen spots, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-008)
    Volkswagen "Snowplow" "Paint" "Animation" "Bus". TRT: 4:00.
  - Smokenders spots, 1978 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-009)
    Smokenders version 3: "Afraid" "So Hard" "I'm Mad" "Isn't Sexy" "Companies" TRT: 2:30.
  - Yugo spots, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-3/4-010)
    Yugo America "Model T" "Garage" "Assembly Line". TRT: 1:30
  - Golden Oldies Pratt Presentation TV/Print. TRT: 10:00., 2003 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-VHS-001)
  - Golden Oldies Pratt Presentation TV/Print. TRT: 10:00., 2003 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-VHS-002)
  - Royal Caribbean presentation, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-VHS-0001, Digital-materials RL11262-SET-0001)
  - Yugo spots, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-VHS-004)
  - Champion International spots, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-VHS-005)
    Champion Paper Product "Broadway" "Retirement". TRT: 2:00
  - Rosenfeld Sirowitz Humphrey Strauss agency reel, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-VHS-006)
    Opium "Deny Yourself Nothing"; Smith Corona "Dr. Ruth"; Bain de Soleil "Delicate Matter"; Colibri "Butterfly"; Delta "Water Ballet" "Color of Delta"; Chase "I'm Sorry"; Champion "Involvement"; Ritz "Krystle/Carrington"; Food Stamps "Mealtimes/Toughtimes". TRT: 10:00
  - Japanese commercials, 1988 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11262-VHS-007)
  - Len Sirowitz show reel, undated (Box AV1, Dvd RL11262-DVD-001)
    Mobil "Ten Story Building" "Driving with My Baby"; Laura Scudder Potato Chips; VW "Snow Plow"; Sara Lee "Nobody Doesn't Like..."
  - 24 ads 1960s, undated (Box AV1, Dvd RL11262-DVD-002)